Guide to the Incoming letters from Jimmy Santiago Baca, Denise Levertov, and "Mariposa", 1976-1987
Department of Special Collections
Incoming letters from Jimmy Santiago Baca, Denise Levertov, and "Mariposa",
1976-1987
Special Collections M0818
Moser, Norm
.25 linear ft. (31 letters)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1995
Biography
Moser was editor of ILLUMINATIONS. Baca, a Chicano, was a prisoner in the Southwest, championed by Levertov. He has since had several books published by New Directions. Mariposa, friend of Baca, is a poet and translator of South American poetry.
Scope and Content
Twenty-four letters, some with poems, from Baca, 1976-1987. From prison in 1977 he writes about learning to write poetry, a prison riot and the national guard storming the prison as he writes. Three letters from Denise Levertov, 1980-1981. Four letters from Mariposa (Virginia Love Long), 1978-1979.
Access Terms
Baca, Jimmy Santiago, 1952-; Levertov, Denise, 1923-; Long, Virginia Love; American Literature-- Mexican American Authors; Mexican American poets; Mexican American prisoners; Prisoner's Writings; Prisons; Mexican American literature (Spanish)
Container List
- Jimmy Santiago Baca (1976 Dec) (Folder 1)
  - 1975, Oct 8Phoenix, AZ, tls 2pp, singlespaced. Env + empty env.
  - 1976, Dec 18Phoenix, AZ, tls 2pp, singlespaced. Env + empty env.
- Jimmy Santiago Baca (1977 Jan - Sept) (Folder 2)
  - 1977, Jan 8Florence, AZ, tls 2pp, including poem "I am Alive". Env.
  - 1977, Feb 4Florence, AZ, tls, 1 1/2 pp, with poem, single-spaced. Env.
  - 1977, March 4Phoenix, AZ, als, 6 pp. Partly in Spanish, with pens. Env.
  - 1977, March 8No Place. tls 1 pg. Unsigned
  - 1977, April 23Phoenix, AZ als, 2 1/2 pp. Env.
  - 1977, May 13Florence, AZ, als, 1 p. Mailed with May 12 letter.
  - 1977, Aug 4Florence, AZ, als, 4 pp. Env.
  - 1977, Sept 7Florence, AZ, tls, 1+ pp. signed in type, single-spaced
  - 1977, Sept 14Florence, AZ, als, 3pp. Env.
  - 1977, Sept 21[Florence, AZ]. tls, 1/2 pg.
- Jimmy Santiago Baca (1978 June - Dec) (Folder 3)
  - 1978, June 10Phoenix, AZ. tls, 2pp. signed in type. Env.
  - 1978, July 16Phoenix, AZ. als, 2pp. Legal size paper. Env.
  - 1978, Dec. 17.[Raleigh, NC] tls, 1 p. Env. With a second letter, an als, 1 p. on Diocese of Raleigh stationery
- Jimmy Santiago Baca (1979 Mar - 1979 Oct) (Folder 4)
  - 1979, March 30Hurdle Mills, NC. tls, 3+ pp. single-spaced. Env.
  - 1979, April 13Albuquerque, NM. tls, 2 pp., single-spaced. Signed in type. Env.
  - 1979, Sept 21Hurdle Mills, NC. tls, 1 p., single-spaced, Env.
  - 1979, Oct 20No Place, tls, 1p + holograph addenda
- Jimmy Santiago Baca (1980 Aug - 1987 Jan) (Folder 5)
  - 1980, Aug. 25Hurdle Mills, NC. tls, 1/2 p. Env. Plus empty env.
  - 1980, Sept 28Hurdle Mills, NC. tls, 1/2 p.
  - 1986, Oct 21Albuquerque, NM. als, 2 pp.
  - 1987, Jan 8Albuquerque, NM. tls, 5pp, with long poem. Env.
- Letters to Norm Moser from Denise Levertov (1980 Oct - 1981 Mar) (Folder 6)
  - 1980, Oct 30Boston, MA. als, 2pp. She used to editor for free poetry submissions to "Mother Jones". But as the magazine is no longer publishing poems, Moser can be sure it is "not holding yours."
  - 1980, Dec 16Boston, MA, tns, 1/3 pg, from Carlene Carrasco, Levertov's secretary; Levertov does not have time to read manuscripts; does not know where Moser can publish his work. Env.
  - 1981, Mar 12Boston, MA. tls, 1/2 pg. from Carlene Carrasco, Levertov's secretary, calling Moser abusive, asking for an apology; with Moser's holograph draft reply, unapologetic. Env.
- Letters to Norm Moser from "Mariposa" - friend of Baca (June 1978 - April 1979) (Folder 7)
  - 1978, June 9Hurdle Mills, NC. Envelope.
  - 1978, Dec 19Raleigh, NC. tls, 1 p. Env. [docketed, "answered all 3"]. Three letters were in this envelope; 2 from Baca, 1 from Mariposa. Envelope is above with Baca letters.
  - 1979, March 16Raleigh, NC. tls, 2 pp. Env.
  - 1979, April 16Hurdle Mills, NC. tls, 1 pg. single-spaced. Env.